Frank G. Speck Papers 1903-1950 Mss.Ms.Coll.126
American Philosophical Society
- Subcollection II. Manuscripts on Native Americans, 1913-1946; 5.5 linear feet
  - Series II. Works by Speck, 1913-1942; 5 Linear Feet
    - Penobscot Man: the Life History of a Forest Tribe in Maine Folder 3, [1940]; 1 item (Box 26)
    - Penobscot Man: the Life History of a Forest Tribe in Maine Folder 4, [1940]; 1 item (Box 26)
    - Penobscot Man: the Life History of a Forest Tribe in Maine Folder 5, [1940]; 1 item (Box 26)
    - Penobscot Man: the Life History of a Forest Tribe in Maine Folder 6 [Page Proofs], [1940]; 1 item (Box 26)
      Galley proofs, with corrections, pages 1 - 100. Images note: 165 photomechanical prints of social life and customs: birk bark containers, baskets, canoes, utensils, drum beater, snow snakes, masks, cradleboards, traps, pipes, diagrams of round dance. (continues in folders 7, 8, to end of galley proofs)
    - Penobscot Man: the Life History of a Forest Tribe in Maine Folder 7 [Page Proofs], [1940]; 1 item (Box 26)
      Galley proofs, with corrections, pages 101 - 224
    - Penobscot Man: the Life History of a Forest Tribe in Maine Folder 8 [Page Proofs], [1940]; 1 item (Box 26)
      Galley proofs, with corrections, pages 225 - 317.
    - "Penobscot Shamanism" Folder 1, [1920]; 1 item (Box 27)
      Handwritten notes, and typed manuscript with annotations.
    - Penobscot Shamanism" Folder 2, [1920]; 1 item (Box 27)
    - "Penobscot Tales and Religious Beliefs" Folder 1, [1935]; 1 item (Box 27)
    - "Penobscot Tales and Religious Beliefs" Folder 2, [1935]; 1 item (Box 27)
    - "Penobscot Tales and Religious Beliefs" Folder 3, [1935]; 1 item (Box 27)
    - "Penobscot Tales and Religious Beliefs" Folder 4, [1935]; 1 item (Box 27)
    - "Penobscot Tales and Religious Beliefs" Folder 5, [1935]; 1 item (Box 27)
    - "Penobscot Transformer Tales", 1918; 1 item (Box 27)
    - "Primitive Cults and Ceremonies"--Lecture, 1917; 1 item (Box 27)
      Typed manuscript
    - "Primitive Religions", [1918]; 1 item (Box 27)
      Typed manuscript with annotations, and notes.
    - "The Probable Eastward Drift of Indians in the Labrador Peninsula", 1 item (Box 28)
      Typed manuscript with annotations. Images note: 2 maps of Maine showing tribal distribution of Montagnais-Naskapi and Eskimos of the Labrador Peninsula.
    - "Public Instruction"--Galley Proofs, n.d.; 1 item (Box 28)
      Galley proofs with annotations
    - "Rappahannock Herbals, Folklore, and Science of Cures" Folder 1, 1942; 1 item (Box 28)
      Typed manuscript with annotations. Written by Speck with Royal B. Hassrick, Edmund S. Carpenter.
    - "Rappahannock Herbals, Folklore, and Science of Cures" Folder 2 [Photocopies], 1942; 1 item (Box 28)
      Photocopies of page proofs with annotations.
    - "Rappahannock Herbals, Folklore, and Science of Cures" Folder 3 [Originals; do not use], 1942; 1 item (Box 28)
      Originals of page proofs with annotations.
    - "Rappahannock Herbals, Folklore, and Science of Cures" Folder 4 [Originals; do not use], 1942; 1 item (Box 28)
    - "The Rappahannock Indians of Virginia", [1925]; 1 item (Box 28)
      Typed manuscript with annotaitons.
    - "Reptile Lore of the Northern Indians", 1917; 1 item (Box 28)
    - "Social Census of the Escoumains Band of Montagnais", 1916; 1 item (Box 28)
    - "The Social Structure of the Northern Algonkian", [1917]; 1 item (Box 28)
    - Societies of the Plains Indians Edited by Clark Wissler--Review, [1918]; 1 item (Box 28)
      Typed manuscript of review.
    - "Some Naskapi Myths From Little Whale River", 1913; 1 item (Box 28)
    - "Spiritual Beliefs Among Labrador Indians", 1924; 2 items (Box 28)
      Handwritten and typed manuscripts.
    - "Studies of the Beothuk and Micmac of Newfoundland" [See also Oversized], 1913; 2 items (Box 28)
    - A Study of the Delaware Indian Big House Ceremony in Native Text Dictated by Witapanoxwe Folder 1, 1930; 1 item (Box 29)
      Typed manuscript with annotations, pgs. 1 - 77.
    - A Study of the Delaware Indian Big House Ceremony in Native Text Dictated by Witapanoxwe Folder 2, 1930, n.d.; 2 items (Box 29)
      Typed manuscript with annotations, pgs. 78 - 107; handwriten manuscript of native text with translations.
    - A Study of the Delaware Indian Big House Ceremony in Native Text Dictated by Witapanoxwe Folder 3, 1 item (Box 29)
      Handwriten manuscript of native text with translations.
    - A Study of the Delaware Indian Big House Ceremony in Native Text Dictated by Witapanoxwe Folder 4, 1 item (Box 29)
    - A Study of the Delaware Indian Big House Ceremony in Native Text Dictated by Witapanoxwe Folder 5, 1 item (Box 29)
      Typed manuscript with annotations, pgs. 1 - 63.
    - A Study of the Delaware Indian Big House Ceremony in Native Text Dictated by Witapanoxwe Folder 6, 2 items (Box 29)
      Typed manuscript with annotations, pgs. 64 - 87; handwriten manuscript of native text with translations. Images note: 16 photomechanical prints of individual portraits, longhouses, rattles, tools, musical instruments, bows and arrows.
    - A Study of the Delaware Indian Big House Ceremony in Native Text Dictated by Witapanoxwe Folder 7, 1929; 2 items (Box 29)
      Handwriten manuscript of native text with translations; typed manuscript with annotations.
    - A Study of the Delaware Indian Big House Ceremony in Native Text Dictated by Witapanoxwe Folder 8, 1929; 1 item (Box 30)
      Typed manuscript with annotations. Images note: 10 sketches of diagrams of dance movements; basket designs.
    - A Study of the Delaware Indian Big House Ceremony in Native Text Dictated by Witapanoxwe Folder 9, 1929; 1 item (Box 30)
    - A Study of the Delaware Indian Big House Ceremony in Native Text Dictated by Witapanoxwe Folder 10, 1928; 1 item (Box 30)
    - A Study of the Delaware Indian Big House Ceremony in Native Text Dictated by Witapanoxwe Folder 11, 1928; 1 item (Box 30)
    - A Study of the Delaware Indian Big House Ceremony in Native Text Dictated by Witapanoxwe Folder 12 [Galley Proofs], 1930; 1 item (Box 30)
    - A Study of the Delaware Indian Big House Ceremony in Native Text Dictated by Witapanoxwe Folder 13 [Galley Proofs], 1930; 1 item (Box 30)
    - A Study of the Delaware Indian Big House Ceremony in Native Text Dictated by Witapanoxwe Folder 14 [Page Proofs], 1931; 1 item (Box 30)
      Page proofs with annotations. Images note: 20 photomechanical prints, 45 color sketches, 6 photographs of false faces, face paintings for dances, rattles, drums, prayer sticks; portrait of Witapanoxwe.
    - A Study of the Delaware Indian Big House Ceremony in Native Text Dictated by Witapanoxwe Folder 15 [Page Proofs], 1928, 1931; 1 item (Box 30)
      Page proofs. Images note: 14 photomechanical prints of maks, rattles, bark containers, masks, diagrams of dance movements.
    - A Study of the Delaware Indian Big House Ceremony in Native Text Dictated by Witapanoxwe Folder 16 [Page Proofs], 1931; 1 item (Box 30)
      Page proofs with annotations. Images note: 28 photomechanical prints of same images as in folder #14.
    - A Study of the Delaware Indian Big House Ceremony in Native Text Dictated by Witapanoxwe Folder 17 [Page Proofs], 1931; 1 item (Box 30)
      Page proofs with annotations. Images note: 106 photomechanical prints of face painting images, some the same as in folder #14.
    - "Testing Folklore by Observations on Butler's Garter Snake", 1917; 2 items (Box 31)
      Typed manuscript with annotations
    - The Tutelo Spirit Adoption Ceremony, Reclothing the Living in the Spirit of the Dead Folder 1, 1942; 1 ietm (Box 31)
    - The Tutelo Spirit Adoption Ceremony, Reclothing the Living in the Spirit of the Dead Folder 2, 1942; 1 item (Box 31)
      Illustrations for manuscript. Images note: 19 sketches of floor plans of adoption ceremony.
    - "Two Araucanian Texts", 1925; 1 item (Box 31)
      Typed manuscript, and handwritten notes of native text.
    - Unknown Tribes, Uncharted Seas By Lady Richmond Brown--Review (Ms.), [1926]; 1 ietm (Box 31)
    - "The Use of Wampum Among the Eastern Tribes of Indians", 1915; 1 item (Box 31)
    - "A Visit to the Pequot Indian Remnants in Connecticut", 1917; 1 item (Box 31)
  - Series III. Field Notes, n.d.; 1 folder
    - Delaware Social Dance Bustle, n.d.; 4 items (Box 31)
      Handwritten field notes. Image note: 1 pencil sketch of pattern of beads on bustle.
  - Series IV. Photographs and Video, 4 folders
    - [Algonkian Birch Bark Containers], n.d.; 7 items (Box 31)
      Images note: 35 photographs of Algonkian birch bark containers from the Smithsonian Institution, Bureau of American Ethnology and the Denver Art Museum.
    - [Algonkian People], n.d.; 2 items (Box 31)
      3 photographs of Algonkian birch bark workers and basket makers of River Desert, P.Q.
    - [Decorative Patterns] See also Oversized, n.d.; 2 items (Box 31)
      2 photographs of patterns for birch bark containers.
    - [Stitching], n.d.; 1 item (Box 31)
      3 sketches of stiching for birch bark containers with tool used.
    - Naskapi films of Frank G. Speck, ca. 1930; 1.0 Item(s) DVD of the 3 reels of Frank Speck film, Film 520
    - Naskapi films of Frank G. Speck, ca. 1930; 1.0 Videotape(s) Original digital tape transfer of 3 reels of film, Film 520